finalsite.net 2012-05-13

# finalsite: web software and services for schools - Private School Websites, Independent School Websites, School Content Management System, Education Content Management System, School Website Design, Private School Software, CMS: Website Privacy Policy

| 

## **Website Privacy Policy**

**Last Updated 4/9/2012**

This privacy statement describes how Active Internet Technologies dba “finalsite” collects and uses the personal information you provide on our Web site: www.finalsite.com. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information.

Thank you for visiting finalsite.com and reviewing our privacy policy. Active Internet Technologies dba “finalsite” has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information.  The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software.   TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact Kathy Venezia at 860.289.3507.  If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact[ TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint).

#### EU and Swiss Safe Harbor Compliancy

finalsite complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland.  finalsite has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement.  To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view finalsite’s certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor>.

#### Information Collection and Use

**Emails and Web Forms**  
We collect information from users of our site and client portal such as name, email, school information, and phone number when you request demos or contact us. Personally identifiable information that you provide by email or web forms will be used only for such purposes as are described at the point of collection (for example on a web form), such as to send information to you or respond to your questions or comments. If you provide contact information, finalsite staff or its contractors may contact you to clarify your comment or question, or to learn about your level of satisfaction with our services. We do not share or sell any personal information to third parties except as described in this privacy policy.

In the event finalsite goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personally identifiable information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via prominent notice on our website for 30 days of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information. ****

**Orders**  
If you register for a finalsite event, we request certain personally identifiable information from you on our order form. You must provide contact information (such as name, email, and school information) and, for chargeable events, financial information (such as credit card number and expiration date). We use this information for billing purposes for event registration or to contact you if we have difficulty processing your order.

**Testimonials**  
Our client contracts include client permission to post testimonials, both written and video, on our website. Permission to display client reference information (name, school, phone number) is obtained from our clients prior to displaying them on our site.

**Surveys**  
Occasionally we may provide you the opportunity to participate in surveys on our site. If you participate we will request certain personally identifiable information from you. Participation in these surveys is entirely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and email address). We use this information to improve our finalsite services and product offerings.

**Share/Email-a-Page**  
If you choose to use the +Share link available at the bottom of most site pages, you will be invoking the AddThis tool which is a third party product enabling you to easily send our website links to other sites or to email a page link to a friend. All personally identifiable information (such as name and email address) you enter here is covered by the AddThis privacy policy, available at <http://www.addthis.com/privacy>.

**Service Providers**  
We use other third parties such as a credit card processor to bill you for goods and services.  For instance, when you register for an event we will share your credit card information with our payment processor as necessary for the third party to provide that service. These third parties are prohibited from using your personally identifiable information for promotional purposes.

#### Information Collected and Stored Automatically

If you do nothing during your visit but browse through our website, read pages, or download information, we will gather and store certain information about your visit automatically using cookies and log files. This information does not identify you personally.  We use this information to help make our site more useful to visitors, to learn about the number of visitors to our site, and the types of technology they use.

**Log Files**  
As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files.  This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.  We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users’ movements around the site, and to gather demographic information about our user base.  **We do not link this automatically collected data to personally identifiable information.**

**Cookies**  
A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record keeping purposes. We use cookies on this site. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site. We use both session ID and persistent cookies. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser, while a persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following the instructions in your browser’s help file. 

We use session cookies to uniquely distinguish your browsing interactions from others so our site functions correctly, and persistent cookies to track and target the interests of our users to enhance your experience on our site. If you reject cookies you may still use our site, but some areas of functionality, such as contests or surveys, may be limited.

**Third Party Cookies**  
We use a third party tracking service, Google Analytics, to capture usage and volume statistics to help improve our site. It uses cookies to track non-personally identifiable information about visitors to our site in the aggregate. The use of cookies by our tracking utility company is not covered by our privacy statement. Additional information about the use of cookies by Google Analytics can be found at <http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html>.

****Web Beacons**  
**

Our Web pages contain electronic images known as Web beacons (sometimes called single-pixel gifs) and are used along with cookies to compile aggregated statistics to analyze how our site is used and may be used in some of our emails to let us know which emails and links have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of our customer communications and marketing campaigns.

#### Communications from finalsite

**Customer Service**  
Based upon the personally identifiable information you provide us, we will send you a welcoming email to verify your username and password. We will also communicate with you in response to your inquiries, to provide the services you request, and to manage your account.  We will communicate with you by email or telephone, in accordance with your wishes.

**Opt-out of Special Offers and Updates**  
We will occasionally send you information on products, services, and promotions. Out of respect for your privacy, we present the option not to receive these types of communications.  If you no longer wish to receive our promotional email communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the unsubscribe instructions included in each newsletter, by emailing us at [education@finalsite.com](mailto:education@finalsite.com), or calling us at 860.289.3507. Our portal users may opt out by clicking on the “My Account” button in the upper left corner of the portal home page, and selecting “My Subscriptions”.  Then under “Current Subscriptions” click on “Email Mailing List Settings”.

#### Updating Personally Identifiable Information

If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, or delete your information by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed at the end of this policy. We will respond to your request within 30 days.

#### Links to Other Sites

Our policy discloses the privacy practices for the finalsite website. However, we do provide links to other websites. When you leave www.finalsite.com you will go to sites outside of our control.  These external sites may send their own cookies to users, collect data, or solicit personal information. The privacy policies and procedures described here for finalsite do not apply to any external links. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of any site you link to from ours, especially if you share any personal information. Be informed. You are the person best qualified to protect your own privacy.

#### Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card number) on our registration forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personally identifiable information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our web site, you can email us at [education@finalsite.com](mailto:education@finalsite.com).

For site security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, finalsite uses software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise cause damage. Unauthorized attempts to upload or change information on this site are strictly prohibited and may be punishable under the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986 and 18 U.S.C. Sec. 1001 and 1030. Information also may be used for authorized law enforcement investigations. Except for the above purposes, no other attempts are made to identify individual users or their usage habits.

#### Data Retention

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at education@finalsite.com.  We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

#### Legal Disclaimer

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our website.

#### Changes in this Privacy Statement

If we decide to change our privacy practices, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the home page, and other places we deem appropriate, so you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.  We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently.  If we change how we use your personally identifiable information we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page.

#### Contact Us

Feel free to contact us regarding this privacy statement at [education@finalsite.com](mailto:education@finalsite.com), by telephone at 860.289.3507, or by postal mail at finalsite, 809 Main Street, East Hartford, CT  06108.   
  
---|---
